<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Thomas Hackl | Coding Biologist</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Add a language label to code chunks in pkgdown articles</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;
pkgdown nicely renders code chunks in your package's documentation
website. However, if you mix in non-R code snippets in your articles, it is
difficult to distinguish R code chunks from those written in other
languages. How nice would it be if each code chunk would have a small label to
indicate its content's language.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        /language-labels-for-pkgdown-code-chunks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/language-labels-for-pkgdown-code-chunks</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Automatically update your publication list using R scholar II - get a PDF</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://alecri.github.io/&quot;&gt;Alessio&lt;/a&gt; apparently read my blog post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://thackl.github.io/automatically-update-publications-with-R-scholar&quot;&gt;how to automatically update your
publication list using R and google scholar&lt;/a&gt;. He contacted me wondering if there
is also a solution to get a PDF. Good question, thanks!
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        /automatically-update-publications-with-R-scholar-II-get-pdf</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/automatically-update-publications-with-R-scholar-II-get-pdf</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Get BUSCO gene descriptions from OrthoDB</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://busco.ezlab.org/&quot;&gt;BUSCO&lt;/a&gt; lacks descriptions of the ortholog groups it searches for. You can query
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.orthodb.org/&quot;&gt;OrthoDB&lt;/a&gt; via its API to map BUSCO IDs and pull the information. Below is a short
R snippet to automate this and produce a nice table.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        /BUSCO-gene-descriptions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/BUSCO-gene-descriptions</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Predict hosts and attachment sites of lysogenic phages</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;
Thanks to new sequencing and assembly strategies, new viral genomes are
currently uncovered on what feels like a daily basis. Virus-host relationships,
however, often remain unclear because most genomes are obtained from community
samples rather than cultures. Here, I describe a way to link phages with a
lysogenic lifestyle to their respective hosts using only sequence information.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        /predicting-hosts-and-attachment-sites-of-lysogenic-phages</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/predicting-hosts-and-attachment-sites-of-lysogenic-phages</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Automatically update your publication list using R scholar</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;
I really dislike tedious tasks like updating my publication list on my
website. So here is a very short script that does the job for me. It uses the R
library &lt;a href=&quot;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=scholar&quot;&gt;scholar&lt;/a&gt; to pull my publications from my google scholar profile. I then
use some quick &amp;amp; dirty string parsing to convert that data into a html
table. I'm sure there are a tons of more elegant ways out there, but this
worked, and only took me minutes to set up.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        /automatically-update-publications-with-R-scholar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/automatically-update-publications-with-R-scholar</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Plotting a ggtree and ggplots side by side</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;
Plotting phylogenies and associated data side by side is a good way to explore
evolutionary patterns in your data.  In this post I will describe my approach
for creating such plots in R using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ggplot2.tidyverse.org/index.html&quot;&gt;ggplot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://guangchuangyu.github.io/software/ggtree/&quot;&gt;ggtree&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thomasp85/patchwork&quot;&gt;patchwork&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        /ggtree-composite-plots</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/ggtree-composite-plots</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Blogging with Emacs Org-Mode and Jekyll</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;
I've been thinking about getting my own blog up for more than a while now, and
finally made it happen! This is is my first post, and it will cover the basics
steps I took to get this site up and running.
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blogging-with-emacs-org-mode-and-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blogging-with-emacs-org-mode-and-jekyll</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
